

9/2017 - PRESENT

KYLE S. GREENE

347.424.3642

kgreene06@gmail.com

www.github.com/kylegreene

linkedin.com/in/kylesheagreene

@anerdydev

Summary

Software Engineer specializing in full-stack development. Experienced with all phases of application development using AGILE and Kanban methodologies. Well versed in Javascript, Java, MySQL, AWS and frameworks. Expert at working in a team setting and leadership.

EDUCATION



BS in Applied Mathematics

Oakland University - 2004

Relevant Courses: Calculus 1-3, Linear Algebra, Object Oriented Programming (Java) I&II, Theory of Computation, Applied Probability and Statistics, Differential Equations, Discrete Math, Number Theory, Mathematical Statistics, Time-Series Econometrics, Economic Forecasting, Mathematical Economics.

M.Ed in Educational Leadership

Tennessee State University - 2011

Professional Experience

Q-up, LLC(Quicken Loans)

Detroit, MI

Established new features into our core application such as change user and change password for overall user experience improvement.

- Engineered a credit score simulation endpoint using Transunion's API and integrated into our native application's API.
- Improved our RESTful API in Java to facilitate faster response times.
- Added custom styling to base application using SASS.
- Converted our application's template driven forms into reactive forms for Angular 5.
- Constructed and implemented the administrative panel for an internal tool from a
- Optimized features in our administrative panel to increase customer service representative engagement by 60%

Freelancing

Individual Contracts

10/2016 - PRESENT

- Start to finish client support from original UX designs to selecting domain and hosting
- Leveraged AWS services to deploy and manage web servers.
- Used Gulp for automating tasks and deploying application to Elastic Beanstalk.
- Used Jenkins to write pipeline scripts to integrate with GitHub.
- Maintain sites' performance budget using Chrome Developer Tools.

Instructor

Various Schools

08/2007 - 12/2016

- AP Computer Science Instructed students in object-oriented programming in Java 7
- Robotics Created as new course instructing students in the practical application of Arduino and Raspberry Pi
- Data Structures & Algorithms Instructed students in for a course in Data Structures and Algorithms
- Led a group of seven teachers through several trainings for integrating technology in the classroom

Technical Skills

Scripting & Languages: Java, Object Oriented JavaScript (ES5/ES6), HTML5, CSS2/3

Frameworks/Libraries: Angular JS, Angular 2/5, React JS, Redux, React Native, Node JS, Express, Bootstrap, Spring Boot, SASS, jQuery

Database: Relational – MySQL, Document – MongoDB

Unit Testing & Automation: Mocha, Chai, Protractor, Jasmine, Karma, Selinium

Build & CLI Tools: Grunt, Gulp, NPM, NVM, Bower

Source Control: Git, GitHub

Other: Jenkins, JIRA, Confluence, AWS(EC2, Lambda, S3, Route 53, Elastic Beanstalk, Cloudfront, Elastic LoadBalancing)



Projects

Fridge, Software Engineer https://github.com/kylegreene/fridgeapp

A Task Management Application for multi-tenant households

Architectural design and implementation of authentication system using JavaScript, React/Redux, and Passport.JS frameworks Implemented UI views as dictated by mockups provided by UX team members using HTML5, CSS3, and Material UI framework Scrum Master for the development team to remove any impediments to delivery, facilitate meetings, and work with the product owner to ensure the project backlog is well defined with features, user stories, acceptance criteria, story points, and tasks

Hang, Software Engineer Hangnyc.herokuapp.com, https://github.com/kylegreene/jestCause

A communication facilitation application for friends to explore user curated events offline

Implement user interface using AngularJS, Flexbox, and Bootstrap Created new routes to improve the flow of data from server to client by using Express.js and Node.js Implemented unit tests and automation tests for the user interface using Selinium

FreeBy, Software Engineer Freeby.herokuapp.com, https://github.com/kylegreene/lookOUT

A location based application used to find events in a user's locale

Implemented a service using Express.js to consume, clean, and decorate data from the EventBrite.com API Developed a deployment Strategy using Heroku

Designed the Landing and event pages using Material UI in conjunction with AngularJS